<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Curiosity</name>
    <icon_image>curiosity_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>curiosity_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Curiosity is the search for information for its own sake. Active open-mindedness means
            exploring a wide range of relevant information when trying to draw a conclusion,
            including information that challenges our own initial assumptions.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About curiosity</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="video">
            <title>Dr. Jon Baron of UPenn talks about "Active Open-minded Thinking" and curiosity</title>
            <cover>curiosity_video_cover</cover>
            <link>http://vimeo.com/89521461</link>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does curiosity look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>When we are curious, we ask questions, search for information, explore our
                    environment, and explore the world in countless ways. People who explore for its
                    own sake wind up knowing more. For example, after seeing a movie about some
                    historical event, they go to Wikipedia to find out what probably really
                    happened.</p>
                    <p>Curiosity feeds into good thinking because it makes us want information, even
                    when the information could cause us to change our minds. People who think this
                    way are more likely to have beliefs that reflect reality and to make decisions
                    that work out for the best. Such further thought requires both looking for
                    reasons why we might be wrong and, if we find them, taking them at face value
                    rather than finding ways to dismiss them.</p>
                    <p>Being curious means:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Eagerness to explore new things</li>
                        <li> Asking questions to deepen understanding</li>
                        <li>Taking an active interest in learning</li>
                    </ul>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build curiosity?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Encourage Questioning</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Adults should encourage questioning and exploration in themselves and others.
                    Adults can help children by answering children’s questions or pointing children
                    in the direction of where to find answers. When children (or other adults) are
                    about to draw a conclusion, adults should encourage them to look for alternative
                    conclusions and to look for reasons on both sides.</p>
                ]]>

            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Read widely</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>The ability to read, and the habit of exploring multiple sources
                    for information, increases the possibilities for search. Children should be
                    encouraged to read as much as possible and as early as possible, and about the
                    topics that are most interesting to them. Adults should seek to expand the set
                    of written materials that they regularly read (e.g., new websites, magazines,
                    newspapers, etc).</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Question your assumptions</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Developing curiosity and active open-mindedness means recognizing
                    your own biases and assumptions. Question these just as you begin to question
                    other conclusions that you have already accepted. Do not stop yourself when you
                    want to find out something. Look it up. The Internet now makes this much easier,
                    but of course we also must think about what we find there, with the same sort of
                    active open-mindedness that we apply to our own conclusions.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
    <assessment_questions length="3">
        <question>Was eager to explore new things</question>
        <question>Asked questions to help s/he learn better</question>
        <question>Took an active interest in learning</question>
    </assessment_questions>
</strength>