<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Gratitude</name>
    <icon_image>gratitude_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>gratitude_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Gratitude refers to appreciation for the benefits we receive from others and the
            desire to reciprocate with our own positive actions.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About gratitude</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="video">
            <title>Dr. Robert Emmons of UC Davis talks about gratitude</title>
            <cover>gratitude_video_cover</cover>
            <link>http://vimeo.com/95882583</link>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does gratitude look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Those who demonstrate gratitude—and those who don’t—see life differently.
                    Individuals demonstrating gratitude tend to emphasize language related to gifts,
                    givers, blessings, fortune, fortunate, and abundance. Ungrateful people, on the
                    other hand, tend to focus on deprivation, deservingness, regrets, lack, need,
                    scarcity, and loss—what they are lacking rather than what they have. For
                    instance, the grateful person might say, “I get to go to class today,” as
                    opposed to, “Why do I have to learn all this useless stuff?”</p>
                    <p>Displaying gratitude looks like:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Recognizing what other people do for you</li>
                        <li>Showing appreciation for opportunities</li>
                        <li>Expressing appreciation by saying thank you</li>
                        <li>Doing nice things for people as a way of saying thank you</li>
                    </ul>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build gratitude?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Keep a gratitude journal</title>
            <content><![CDATA[
                A group of researchers created an exercise in which individuals wrote down three
                good things that happened to them that day before going to bed. These can be large
                or small. Next to each, they jotted down why the good thing happened.

                Another group of researchers suggest the following: “There are many things in our
                lives, large and small, that we might be grateful about. Think back over the past
                week and write up to five things that happened for which you are grateful or
                thankful.” Keep these reflections in a character journal and complete this activity
                at the end of each week.
            ]]></content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Write a gratitude letter</title>
            <content><![CDATA[
                The benefits of gratitude letters, along with examples of gratitude activities, can
                be found in the research of Dr. Robert Emmons, Dr. Chris Peterson, Dr. Martin
                Seligman, Dr. Sonja Lyubomirsky, and Dr. Jaime Kurtz. Spend fifteen minutes writing
                a gratitude letter to a person in your life who you have never properly thanked.
                This can be thanking him or her for something large or small. Try to be as detailed
                as possible about what you are thanking her for and the impact it had on you. If
                possible, deliver the letter in person and read it to them.
            ]]></content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Train yourself to substitute grateful thoughts for ungrateful ones</title>
            <content><![CDATA[
                Dr. Timothy Miller developed a four-step behavioral cognitive approach for learning
                gratitude: 1. Identify non-grateful thoughts. 2. Formulate gratitude-supporting
                thoughts. 3. Substitute the gratitude-supporting thoughts for the non-grateful
                thoughts. 4. Translate this gratitude into outward action.
            ]]></content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Give back</title>
            <content><![CDATA[
                Dr. Charles Shelton suggests reflecting on benefits and blessings in your life and
                considering ways to give back to others as an appropriate response for the gratitude
                felt. Naikan therapy, for instance, requires practitioners to reflect on what others
                have provided to them and what they have given back; in so doing, it creates
                feelings of gratitude, indebtedness, and the motivation to reciprocate.
            ]]></content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Have even young children illustrate gratitude</title>
            <content><![CDATA[
                Children are very visual. Have your child draw a picture of what he or she is
                thankful for today. You might even have them build a gratitude wall in their room by
                posting all the pictures that they draw over the course of a month. Try to include
                discussion of the pictures and the wall in everyday conversations.
            ]]></content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
    <assessment_questions>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>Recognized what other people did for them<br />
                Showed appreciation for opportunities<br />
                Expressed appreciation by saying thank you<br />
                Did something nice for someone else as a way of saying thank you</p>
        ]]>
    </assessment_questions>
</strength>