<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Grit</name>
    <icon_image>grit_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>grit_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Grit is perseverance and passion for long-term goals.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About grit</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="video">
            <title>Dr. Angela Duckworth of UPenn talks about grit</title>
            <cover>grit_video_cover</cover>
            <link>http://vimeo.com/89521167</link>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does grit look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Grit is a combination of passion and persistence. Having grit means
                    pursuing your goal with vigor and focus over an extended period of time. Less
                    gritty individuals are easily discouraged or frequently led off track by new
                    interests.</p>
                    <p>Being gritty means:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Finishing what you begin</li>
                        <li>Staying committed to your goals</li>
                        <li>Working hard even after experiencing failure or when you feel like
                        quitting</li>
                        <li>Sticking with a project or activity for more than a few weeks</li>
                    </ul>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build grit?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What to be mindful of</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>It’s important to know that there are still a lot of open questions about
                    grit, including the degree to which it is a teachable skill and, to the extent
                    it can be learned, how best to teach it. Though the research about grit is still
                    emerging, we do have some ideas about how you might develop grit.</p>
                ]]>

            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Cultivate a growth mindset and optimism</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>We believe that the idea of grit is related to both optimism and a growth
                    mindset. When you believe that setbacks are temporary and that problems are
                    surmountable with effort and ingenuity, you’ll likely try harder, or try another
                    tactic, when you encounter obstacles.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Challenge yourself in your practice</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Research on world-class experts in music, sports, chess, and other domains
                    suggest that thousands of hours of deliberate practice are necessary to achieve
                    the highest skill level. Often, when we look at those who are successful in
                    their field, we don’t see the hidden hours of gritty and grueling practice it
                    took to get there. We believe that productive practice should focus on
                    weaknesses, feel difficult, be repetitive, and include immediate and informative
                    feedback.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Stay passionate about your purpose</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Grit isn’t just hard work and persistence—it’s also passion for a personally
                    meaningful goal. Determine the topic or activity that captures your attention
                    the most, and work on developing grit in that area. We suggest enhancing your
                    practice and interest by working with role models, coaches, and peers to develop
                    that interest and skill over time.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Know it’s OK to quit</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Not every piano-playing ten-year-old will become a piano-playing
                    twenty-year-old. It’s OK to quit activities, but choose the right time to quit:
                    after you’ve been thoughtful and reflective, and definitely not in a moment of
                    frustration. Gritty people know the difference between the two and quit
                    responsibly.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
    <assessment_questions>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>Finished whatever s/he began<br />
                Stuck with a project or activity for more than a few weeks<br />
                Tried very hard even after experiencing failure<br />
                Stayed committed to goals<br />
                Kept working hard even when s/he felt like quitting</p>
            </ul>
        ]]>
    </assessment_questions>
</strength>