<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Optimism</name>
    <icon_image>optimism_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>optimism_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Optimism is the expectation that the future holds positive possibilities and the
            confidence that, with effort, these possibilities become likelihoods.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About optimism</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does optimism look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Optimists and pessimists see problems differently. Optimists tend
                    to focus on causes that are temporary and changeable, while pessimists focus on
                    causes that are permanent or fixed. For example, after receiving a low grade on
                    a math test, an optimist may conclude that s/he didn’t study enough, while a
                    pessimist may conclude that s/he has no ability in math. These different
                    thinking styles profoundly affect how people cope with problems (for example,
                    whether they study harder or give up).</p>
                    <p>Being optimistic means:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Believing that effort will improve your future</li>
                        <li>When bad things happen, thinking about what you could do to avoid
                        similar bad outcomes in the future</li>
                        <li>Staying motivated, even when things don’t go well</li>
                    </ul>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build optimism?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Adopt a growth mindset</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Optimism reflects the tendencies to: 1) attribute problems to temporary and
                    changeable causes; 2) expect good things from others, the world, and the future,
                    and 3) believe that we can work to overcome obstacles and achieve our goals.
                    Optimism is therefore very closely related to what Carol Dweck and colleagues
                    call&nbsp;<a href="http://characterlab.org/growth-mindset/">
                    <em>growth mindset</em></a>—the belief that the ability to learn is itself
                    something that can be improved with effort.</p>
                ]]>

            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Create caring environments</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Children are more likely to develop optimism when they grow up in
                    caring environments. Parenting behaviors that convey affection predict the
                    development of optimism in children, perhaps because children learn to expect
                    that others will care about them and treat them well.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Model optimism in actions and language</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Some research suggests that children may internalize optimism from their
                    parents. When we encounter problems in our own lives, we can model optimism by
                    conveying our belief that the problems will pass or that we can work to address
                    them. When talking with our children about mistakes they have made or problems
                    they have helped to create, we can focus on the specific behaviors that
                    contributed, especially behaviors they can change.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Find (or create) opportunities to overcome adversity</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Optimism also develops through personal experiences of working hard to
                    achieve goals and to overcome challenges. These experiences increase children’s
                    sense of control and competence and demonstrate that effort pays off. The right
                    level of challenge will vary by age and by child. As parents, we can support our
                    children as they take on greater and greater challenges.</p>
                    <p>Parents naturally want to protect our children from difficult and painful
                    experiences. Yet, these experiences are inevitable. And to some extent they are
                    probably necessary for optimism to develop. It can help to keep in mind that the
                    difficult situations our children encounter can provide opportunities for them
                    to learn that many problems are temporary and surmountable.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Learn basic cognitive behavioral therapy strategies</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Programs like the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ppc.sas.upenn.edu/prpsum.htm">
                    Penn Prevention Program</a>&nbsp;can help. In the program, students are taught
                    basic cognitive behavioral therapy strategies for thinking about the causes of
                    events in a more optimistic fashion.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
    <assessment_questions length="4">
        <question>Believed that effort would improve his/her future</question>
        <question>When bad things happened, s/he thought about things they could do to make it better next time</question>>
        <question>Stayed motivated, even when things didn’t go well</question>
        <question>Believed that s/he could improve on things they weren’t good at</question>
    </assessment_questions>
</strength>