<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Self-Control</name>
    <icon_image>self_control_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>self_control_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Self-control is the capacity to regulate thoughts, feelings, or behaviors when they
            conflict with valued goals.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About self-control</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="video">
            <title>Dr. Ethan Kross of the University of Michigan talks about self-control</title>
            <cover>self_control_video_1_cover</cover>
            <link>http://vimeo.com/96232700</link>
        </item>
        <item type="video">
            <title>Dr. Walter Mischel of Columbia University talks about self-control</title>
            <cover>self_control_video_2_cover</cover>
            <link>http://vimeo.com/89521169</link>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does self-control look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Those who demonstrate self-control—and those who don’t—have
                    different responses to tempting stimuli or otherwise challenging environments.
                    Someone displaying self-control can delay short-term temptations that interfere
                    with longer-term aspirations, whereas someone displaying low self-control will
                    succumb to those temptations. For instance, someone with high self-control who
                    aims to run a marathon will not press the snooze button on their morning alarm
                    clock and will instead rise out of bed and follow through with a scheduled
                    workout.</p>
                    <p>Demonstrating self-control looks like:</p>
                    <p><strong>In Work/School</strong>: &nbsp;Coming to office/class with everything
                    needed to get to work, as opposed to being unprepared · Remembering and
                    following directions rather than needing to be reminded  · Getting to work right
                    away rather than procrastinating · Paying attention rather than getting
                    distracted</p>
                    <p><strong>Interpersonally</strong>: Remaining calm even when criticized or
                    otherwise provoked, rather than losing one’s temper · Allowing others to speak
                    rather than interrupting · Being polite to all, as opposed to speaking
                    harshly</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build self-control?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Choose your environment wisely</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Select the environment that will be most beneficial to you. For instance,
                    after the school day ends, students may retreat to their family’s living room,
                    where the temptation of TV might be very strong—or they can go to the library,
                    which is designed to eliminate distractions.</p>
                ]]>

            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Tweak your environment to minimize distractions</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Tweak the environment you find yourself in to obtain your desired outcome.
                    For instance, while in a conference or in class, sit closer to the presenter
                    and/or farther from noisy attendees/classmates. Another strategy can be to place
                    your cell phone out of sight to avoid being distracted during class, work, or
                    meals.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Shift your focus</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>If you find yourself in a distracting or frustrating situation, shift your
                    focus to something that helps you achieve your desired emotional state. This can
                    be either an internal or an external focus. For instance, while in a boring
                    meeting, an external shift would be to track the person who is talking by
                    looking directly at them, rather than staring out the window. An internal
                    approach would be to think about upcoming vacation plans to avoid falling
                    asleep.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Shift your frame</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Reinterpret the situation to alter your emotional state. For instance, rather
                    than thinking of a mistake as a personal shortcoming or failure, think of
                    mistakes as information that will help you in the future. Also consider framing
                    certain trying situations as opportunities to exercise and grow your
                    willpower.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Plan your response</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Think proactively about how you might best respond in a stressful situation,
                    keeping in mind effective practices including deep breathing, suppressing an
                    undesired behavior, or emulating people you admire.</p>
                    <p>One proven strategy is to plan out IF/THEN scenarios to overcome obstacles.
                    For instance, when trying to stick to a healthy lifestyle, don’t just hope to go
                    to the gym: plan exactly when in the day you will go and specifically what you
                    will do to exercise. The same is true for negative feelings: ”IF I start to feel
                    angry, THEN I will take a deep breath and start counting backward from a 100
                    (until I calm down and think before I act).”</p>
                    <p>Another promising strategy is to refer to yourself in the third person when
                    upset (sometimes called the “say your name” strategy).</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
</strength>