<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Social Intelligence</name>
    <icon_image>social_intelligence_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>social_intelligence_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Social intelligence refers to awareness of other people’s motives and feelings as well
            as using this understanding to navigate social situations appropriately.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About self-control</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does social intelligence look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>People with high levels of social intelligence have an awareness of other
                    people’s feelings and motives and use this understanding to navigate social
                    situations appropriately, whereas those low on social intelligence are less
                    attuned to other people’s feelings and perspectives. For instance, someone
                    displaying socially intelligent behavior would recognize a shift in someone’s
                    tone or demeanor and might adjust his or her own behavior accordingly.</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Find solutions during conflicts with others</li>
                        <li>Demonstrate respect for the feelings of others</li>
                        <li>Adapt to different social situations</li>
                    </ul>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build social intelligence?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What to be mindful of</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>It’s important to know that there are still a lot of open questions about
                    social intelligence, including the degree to which it is a teachable skill, and,
                    to the extent it can be learned, how best to teach it. Though the research about
                    social intelligence is still emerging, we do have some ideas about how you might
                    develop social intelligence.</p>
                ]]>

            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Provide active and constructive responses</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Respond to people in an active and constructive way to build strong
                    relationships. For instance, rather than saying something discouraging or
                    nothing at all to your child, student, co-worker, parent, or friend, follow up
                    on what s/he said with what Dr. Shelly Gable and others call an
                    <a href="http://www.psych.rochester.edu/people/reis_harry/assets/pdf/GableReisImpettAsher_2004.pdf">
                    “active and constructive response.”</a></p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Learn about social-emotional learning programs</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Consider integrating social-emotional learning programs that consist of
                    “step-by-step approaches that actively involve students in skills development
                    over extended periods of time and have clear and explicit goals” into your
                    school, and implement them with fidelity. The
                    <a href="http://ccsr.uchicago.edu/sites/default/files/publications/Noncognitive%20Report.pdf">
                    University of Chicago says that programs comprised of these attributes tend to
                    be particularly effective</a>.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
</strength>