<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<strength>
    <name>Zest</name>
    <icon_image>zest_circle</icon_image>
    <hero_image>zest_hero</hero_image>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
            Zest, sometimes referred to as vitality, is an approach to life filled with excitement
            and energy.
        ]]>
    </description>
    <about_title>About zest</about_title>
    <about_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What does zest look like?</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Those with high levels of zest are full of life and energy, whereas those on
                    the other end of the spectrum are generally lethargic and resigned. People with
                    zest approach setbacks and serendipitous moments with enthusiasm. This
                    excitement can help energize people around them. For instance, when
                    participating in a brainstorming exercise, someone with zest might talk about
                    ideas excitedly, encourage participants to share their ideas, and then help to
                    build on those ideas.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </about_items>
    <build_title>How to build zest?</build_title>
    <build_items>
        <item type="text">
            <title>What to be mindful of</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>It’s important to know that there are still a lot of open questions about
                    zest, including the degree to which it is a teachable skill and, to the extent
                    it can be learned, how best to teach it. Though the research about zest is still
                    emerging, we do have some ideas about how you might develop zest.</p>
                ]]>

            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Exercise!</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Make a concerted effort to exercise because physical activity can increase
                    your energy and vitality.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Refuel</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Get a good night’s sleep and eat a healthy breakfast.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Become one with nature</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Find time to engage with the natural environment, as contact with nature can
                    influence vitality.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Gain autonomy</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Play an active role in your decisions, because greater autonomy tends to lead
                    to greater energy and engagement.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
        <item type="text">
            <title>Do what you love</title>
            <content>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Dr. Jonathan Haidt suggests doing something because you want to do it, not
                    because you have to do it. &nbsp;Find your passion. What do you love to do? If
                    you already know what your passion is, then build time for it in your schedule.
                    If you don’t, then try to discover it. What did you love to do when you were
                    younger? Try it again now.</p>
                ]]>
            </content>
        </item>
    </build_items>
    <assessment_questions>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>Actively participated<br />
                Showed enthusiasm<br />
                Approached new situations with excitement and energy</p>
        ]]>
    </assessment_questions>
</strength>